Guide to the Richard H. Rickard Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Richard H. Rickard papers
1849-1927
1863-1885
MS 416
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10
(14 boxes, 1 folio)
Correspondence, financial papers, maps, and photographs of Richard H. Rickard, a mining agent and broker in Michigan, South Carolina, and other states, 1863-1885.
Rickard, Richard H., d. 1885
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Edward Eberstadt, 1957.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Correspondence. II. Volumes and Miscellanea.
Biographical / Historical
Mining agent and broker; an obituary described him as "a pioneer broker and mining man of New York and the Michigan copper district"; he is listed in Trow's New York City Directory from 1859-1884 with his occupations variously listed as mining agent, treasurer, secretary, broker, banker; his office was on Nassau St., and later on Pine St.; his residence in Brooklyn, and later in Stamford, Ct.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, financial papers, maps, and photographs of Richard H. Rickard, a mining agent and broker in Michigan, South Carolina, and other states, 1863-1885.
Business; Copper mines and mining; Mines and mineral resources; Mining corporations; Mineral industries -- Finance; Middle West; Maps; Photoprints; Mineral industries; Rickard, Richard H., d. 1885; Eureka Consolidated Mining Company; French Creek Copper Company; Globe Copper Company; Houghton Mineral Land and Mining Company
- Correspondence, Series I
  - Mining companies
    - Belmont Mining Company
      - McDermott, Walter, 1880, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Trent, L. C., 1880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Calumet and Hecla Mining Company, 1881, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Eureka Consolidated Mining Company
      - Bell, E. M., 1879-1881 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
      - Eckart, W. R., 1883 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Jacobus, P., 1883 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Joseph, M. H., 1882-1883, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
      - Locan, F., 1881-1883 (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
      - McKenzie, John C., 1879-1884 (Box 1, Folder 15-20)
      - Read, Thomas J., 1882-1883 (Box 1, Folder 21-23)
      - Simpkins, C. H., 1881-1884 (Box 2, Folder 24-27)
      - Traylor, W. W., 1881-1882 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Willson, Ed. H., 1884 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Eureka Iron and Steel Works, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - French Creek Copper Company
      - Keen, John, 1879-1885 (Box 2, Folder 31-36)
      - Kennaday, Chester, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Matters, James, 1880-1884 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Noble, William, 1880-1881 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Rodda, John, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Hope Copper Company
      - Davis, Jonathan W., 1864-1965 (Box 2, Folder 41-44)
    - Houghton Mineral Land and Mining Company
      - Ball, Dan H., 1878-1879, 1881-1884 (Box 2, Folder 45-50)
      - Chandler, John H., 1882 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - Hoffman, M. H., 1875, 1883-1884 (Box 3, Folder 52-53)
      - Mapes, E. J., 1882 (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - Profit estimate, 1884 (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - Schwitzer, Joseph, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - Stewart, John, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 57)
      - Turner, James M., 1882-1883 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - H. H. Noble and Company
      General
      See: box 3, folder 72
    - International Silver Mining Company
      - Act of incorporation, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Maid of the Mist, Silverton, Colorado
      - Murdoch, James, 1884 (Box 3, Folder 60)
      - Angus Smith and Company, 1880, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Manhattan Mining Company
      - Green, A. A., 1881 (Box 3, Folder 62)
      - Parsons, L. P., 1864-1866 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Marquette and Ontonagon Railroad Company, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Michigamme Mines
      - Lyon, James B., 1879 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Natick Copper Company
      - Goodell, R. R., 1904-1906 (Box 3, Folder 66)
      - Crawford, James, 1874-1879 (Box 3, Folder 67)
      - Harrington, J. T., 1878 (Box 3, Folder 68)
      - Miscellanea, 1877-1927 (Box 3, Folder 69)
      - Nichols, F. W., 1909, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - New York and Michigan Silver Lead Company, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - H. H. Noble and Company, 1879 (Box 3, Folder 72-78)
    - H. H. Noble and Company, 1880-1881 (Box 4, Folder 79-98)
    - H. H. Noble and Company, 1882-1884 (Box 5, Folder 99-106)
    - Penobscot and Smow Drift Consolidated Mining Company
      - Devereaux, J. R., 1881, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 107)
      - Miscellanea, 1878, 1880 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Perkiomen Mining Company, 1863 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Pontiac Mining Company, 1859 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Silver Islet
      - Cattanach, A. J., 1881 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - South Carolina Land and Improvement Company
      - Mackay, J. M., 1876-1877, 1879 (Box 5, Folder 112-113)
      - Bill to charter, 1876 (Box 5, Folder 114)
      - Bill to incorporate, 1876 (Box 5, Folder 115)
      - Southern, J. P., 1877-1878 (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Stamford Mining Company
      - Articles of Assn., 1873 (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Starr-Grove Silver Mining Company (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Customers and stockholders
    - Archer, R., 1884 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Beach, H. B., 1881, 1884 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Bennett, Williams, 1883-1884 (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Borgo and Corgan, 1881 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Burnham, W. A., 1881-1884 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Butler, J. P. M., 1881-1882 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Chandler, Joseph H., 1878-1882 (Box 6, Folder 125-129)
    - Clark, C. D. (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - Clark, J. W., 1879-1880, 1882, undated (Box 6, Folder 131-134)
    - Colwell, B., 1882 (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Commerce Mining Company, 1873 (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Crawford, James, 1878-1881 (Box 6, Folder 137-140)
    - Daniell, John, 1878-1885 (Box 6, Folder 141-147)
    - Davis, Charlie L., 1883-1884 (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - Dunn, William H., 1883-1884 (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Dunstan, Thomas B., 1880, 1884 (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - Edwards, William, 1881, 1883 (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - Hodgson, John C., 1877-1885 (Box 6, Folder 152-160)
    - Mabie, E. W., 1881, 1884 (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - Towar, E. H., 1879 (Box 6, Folder 162)
  - General
    - Allan, Charles F., 1883-1884 (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Ames, J. A., 1878-1879, 1884 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Anderson, James, 1881-1882, undated (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Arens, W., 1880-1885 (Box 7, Folder 166-167)
    - Barclay, William L., 1884 (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Beck, Frederick, 1880-1882 (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Beesley, George, 1864-1865 (Box 7, Folder 170-171)
    - Bevan, Jackson, 1866-1885, undated (Box 7, Folder 172-173)
    - Bigelow, A. P., 1879-1883 (Box 7, Folder 174-175)
    - Bioren and Company, 1883, 1884 (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - Blaine, John S., 1875-1885 (Box 7, Folder 177-183)
    - Blandy, J. F., 1880, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 184)
    - Boyd, Alex, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 185)
    - Buckland, D. C., 1882-1883 (Box 8, Folder 186)
    - S. P. Burt and Company, 1883-1884 (Box 8, Folder 187)
    - Butterworth, W. R., 1880, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 188)
    - Buzzo, J. W., 1879-1880 (Box 8, Folder 189)
    - Chadbourne, Thomas L., 1878-1885 (Box 8, Folder 190)
    - Chynoweth, B. F., Chynoweth, John, 1874-1885 (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - Condon, William, 1882-1885 (Box 8, Folder 192)
    - Crosby, Charles, 1882 (Box 8, Folder 193)
    - Danicle, John, 1884 (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - Davis, William, 1882, 1884 (Box 8, Folder 195)
    - Dee, James R., 1883 (Box 8, Folder 196)
    - Dickinson, William E., 1879-1883 (Box 8, Folder 197-198)
    - Edwards, T. W., 1879-1880 (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - Eureka Iron Company, 1883-1884 (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Everitt, Charles A., 1880, 1882 (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - Farwell, J. E., 1879, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 202)
    - Ferguson, Walton, 1879, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - Fitzgerald, Louis, 1880-1885 (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - Fletcher, W. S., 1883 (Box 8, Folder 205)
    - Forster, John N., 1884-1885 (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - Forster, William T., 1880, 1881, 1884 (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - Gibson, J. M., 1879 (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - Glidden, Jonathan, 1882-1883 (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - Goard, William, 1883-1884 (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - Goodell, R. R., 1879-1884 (Box 8, Folder 211-212)
    - Gould, L. A., 1881 (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - Hanington, John B., 1883 (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - Hard, Alfred A., 1879-1884 (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - Harris, S. B., 1878-1885 (Box 8, Folder 216-218)
    - Harris, William, 1881-1883 (Box 9, Folder 219)
    - Heaverrich, Samuel, 1880-1883 (Box 9, Folder 220)
    - Herring, James R., 1879-1883 (Box 9, Folder 221)
    - Hodge, Samuel F., 1883 (Box 9, Folder 222)
    - Hodgson, David, 1880, 1882 (Box 9, Folder 223)
    - Hodgson, J. P., 1878-1883 (Box 9, Folder 224)
    - Hodgson, Jonathan, 1878-1885 (Box 9, Folder 225-227)
    - Hodgson, Sumner and Company, 1880-1882 (Box 9, Folder 228)
    - Hooper, Thomas, 1879 (Box 9, Folder 229)
    - Hornblower and Page, 1883-1884 (Box 9, Folder 230)
    - Horton, Silas R., 1881 (Box 9, Folder 231)
    - Houghton, Jacb, 1881-1884 (Box 9, Folder 232-233)
    - Hubbell, Jay A., 1878-1879 (Box 9, Folder 234)
    - Hulbert, Francis C., Hulbert, Edwin, 1882 (Box 9, Folder 235)
    - James, Josiah, 1881, 1883 (Box 9, Folder 236)
    - Johnson, W. M., 1883 (Box 9, Folder 237)
    - Key, Susannah, 1880 (Box 9, Folder 238)
    - Lamson, A. D., 1883 (Box 9, Folder 239)
    - Loranger, Stephen, 1880, 1883 (Box 9, Folder 240)
    - Low, Chauncey E., 1883 (Box 9, Folder 241)
    - Lasier and Company, 1879-1887 (Box 9, Folder 242)
    - Loving, E. T., 1879-1884 (Box 9, Folder 243)
    - Mackay, John M., 1881, 1883 (Box 9, Folder 244)
    - McDougall, Joseph E., 1871-1872 (Box 9, Folder 245)
    - McKeyes, B. Y., 1875-1879 (Box 10, Folder 246)
    - Martyn, Henry J., 1884, 1885 (Box 10, Folder 247)
    - Mason, E. L., 1883, 1885 (Box 10, Folder 248)
    - Mathews, George B., 1880 (Box 10, Folder 249)
    - Meads, Alfred, 1883-1885 (Box 10, Folder 250)
    - Miller, Sidney D., Sibley, Frederick T., 1881-1885, undated (Box 10, Folder 251-252)
    - Moss, George W., 1881-1885 (Box 10, Folder 253)
    - Newcombe, William, 1883 (Box 10, Folder 254)
    - Nolan, Kate, 1883, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 255)
    - Northey, Edward, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 256)
    - Northrup, W. A., 1882, 1883 (Box 10, Folder 257)
    - Olds, S. S., 1883 (Box 10, Folder 258)
    - Olney, Henry C., 1882 (Box 10, Folder 259)
    - Palmer, C. H., 1879, 1883 (Box 10, Folder 260)
    - Palmer, William B., 1856, 1858, 1868 (Box 10, Folder 261)
    - Pascoe, John, 1881-1884 (Box 10, Folder 262)
    - Penberthy, E. R., 1883, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 263)
    - Penobscot and Snowdrift Consolidated Mining Company, 1883 (Box 10, Folder 264)
    - William Penn Building and Loan Association, 1883 (Box 10, Folder 265)
    - Perkins, Thomas H., 1881, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 266)
    - Alfred P. Phelps and Company, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 267)
    - Pierce, James M., 1883 (Box 10, Folder 268)
    - Pilgrim, Henry, 1882, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 269)
    - Pontiac Gold Company, 1865-1866 (Box 10, Folder 270)
    - Post, Hoyt, 1882-1884 (Box 10, Folder 271)
    - Raht, Charles, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 272)
    - Rasch, August, 1880 (Box 10, Folder 273)
    - Rickaird estate
      - Gay, J.E., 1881-1889 (Box 10, Folder 274)
    - Rogers, A. N., 1879-1883 (Box 10, Folder 275)
    - Rolston, R. G., 1882 (Box 10, Folder 276)
    - Ryan, William, 1879-1881 (Box 10, Folder 277)
    - Seager, James H., 1880 (Box 10, Folder 278)
    - Seager, S. F., 1879-1881 (Box 10, Folder 279)
    - Seaman, F. A., 1881, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 280)
    - Senter, John, 1868-1880 (Box 10, Folder 281)
    - Senter, Lizzie T., 1879 (Box 10, Folder 282)
    - Seymour, James M., 1879 (Box 10, Folder 283)
    - Simpkins, C. H., 1884 (Box 11, Folder 284)
    - Smith, S. L., 1878-1884, undated (Box 11, Folder 285-287)
    - South Carolina Lands, 1875, 1879 (Box 11, Folder 288)
    - Stevens, F. S., 1883, 1885 (Box 11, Folder 289)
    - Stevens, William H., 1881, 1883, undated (Box 11, Folder 290)
    - Steward Iron Mining Company, 1883, 1884 (Box 11, Folder 291)
    - Stewart, William S., 1884 (Box 11, Folder 292)
    - Street, W. A., 1880-1881 (Box 11, Folder 293)
    - Strong, J. W., 1881, 1882 (Box 11, Folder 294)
    - Sturgis, J. B., 1879, 1884 (Box 11, Folder 295)
    - Sumner, George, 1881-1884 (Box 11, Folder 296)
    - Tompkins, M., 1875, 1877 (Box 11, Folder 297)
    - Trask, Spencer, 1878, 1879 (Box 11, Folder 298)
    - Trelease, Jonathan, 1881 (Box 11, Folder 299)
    - Trethewey, Richard, 1879-1884 (Box 11, Folder 300)
    - Uren, William G., 1885 (Box 11, Folder 301)
    - Van Orden, M., 1881 (Box 11, Folder 302)
    - Van Tassel, Howard A., 1883-1884 (Box 11, Folder 303)
    - Warner, W. S., 1882-1884 (Box 11, Folder 304)
    - Wetherall, William, 1881, 1883 (Box 11, Folder 305)
    - White, F. G., 1878-1883 (Box 11, Folder 306)
    - Williams, E. T., 1880-1882 (Box 11, Folder 307)
    - Wills, Thomas R., 1878-1883 (Box 11, Folder 308-309)
- Volumes and Miscellanea, Series II
  - Letterpress copybooks and letterbooks
    - 1874 July-1876 November (Box 12, Folder 310-314)
    - 1876 November-1878 September (Box 13, Folder 315-318)
    - 1881 October-1885 January (Box 14, Folder 319-321)
  - Photograph album, 1870s (Box 14, Folder 322)
  - Metal plates, Undated (Box 14, Folder 323)
  - Miscellanea
    - 1857-1884 July (Box 15, Folder 324-334)
    - 1884 August-1913, undated (Box 16, Folder 335-339)
  - "Map of Property of the Globe Copper Mining Company, and Mines in the Portage Lake District" (New York: J.O. Seymour and Co.), and Land Office allotment certificates from the United States and the Province of Ontario, 1849-1872 (Box 17, Folder 335-339)